<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Data>
  <Folders>
    <Folder>
      <Title>Programmers Guide</Title>
      <Description>This programmers guide for Apose.Email includes examples covering following topics: 

- Programming Email
- Programming Outlook
- Programming Exchange
- Programming Thunderbird
- Programming Email Verify</Description>
      <FolderName>programmersguide</FolderName>
      <Order>1</Order>
      <Folders>
        <Folder>
          <Title>Programming Email</Title>
          <Description>This section includes examples related to following topics:

- Introduction to Aspose.Email
- Usage scenarios for Aspose.Email.Mail
- Features of Aspose.Email.Mime
- Features of Aspose.Email.Pop3
- Features of Aspose.Email.Imap
- Features of Aspose.Email.Exchange
- Getting started with Programming Email
- Sending Email Messages with SMTP
- Managing Email Messages with POP3
- Managing Emails with IMAP
- Managing Email Message Files with MailMessage
- Aspose.Email HowTos</Description>
          <FolderName>programmingemail</FolderName>
          <Order>1</Order>
          <Examples>
            <Example>
              <Title>Create new Email</Title>
              <Description>Aspose.Email enables the developers to create the Mime ( Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions ) Messages from scratch. The main class for this purpose in Aspose.Email API is MailMessage class. This example explains the steps required for creating email messages in EML, MSG and MTH file formats using Aspose.Email.</Description>
              <FolderName>createnewemail</FolderName>
              <Order>2</Order>
              <DocLink>
                <DisplayName>Create new Email</DisplayName>
                <Url>http://www.aspose.com/docs/display/EmailJava/Create+new+Email</Url>
              </DocLink>
              <OutputFiles>
                <DataFile>
                  <Path>..\data\Message.eml</Path>
                </DataFile>
                <DataFile>
                  <Path>..\data\Message.mhtml</Path>
                </DataFile>
                <DataFile>
                  <Path>..\data\Message.msg</Path>
                </DataFile>
              </OutputFiles>
              <Type>Console</Type>
            </Example>
            <Example>
              <Title>Save message as Draft</Title>
              <Description>Draft is an unfinished message that is not sent yet, rather it is stored in a separate folder for future. Using the Aspose.Email API, the programmer can create a message using the MailMessage class and store it on disk using the MapiMessage class. The email message stored as Draft will always be of Outlook (.MSG) format. This example depicts this usage in detail using Aspose.Email API.</Description>
              <FolderName>savemessageasdraft</FolderName>
              <Order>3</Order>
              <DocLink>
                <DisplayName>Save message as Draft</DisplayName>
                <Url>http://www.aspose.com/docs/display/EmailJava/Save+message+as+Draft</Url>
              </DocLink>
              <OutputFiles>
                <DataFile>
                  <Path>..\data\New-Draft.msg</Path>
                </DataFile>
              </OutputFiles>
              <Type>Console</Type>
            </Example>
          </Examples>
          <Folders>
            <Folder>
              <Title>Sending Email Messages with SMTP</Title>
              <Description>This section includes the examples related to following topics: 

- Sending Emails
- Load Smtp Authentication Information from Config File
- Connecting to SSL enabled Smtp Server
- Specifying Multiple Recipients
- Set Mail Body
- Managing Email Attachments
- Send Meeting Requests
- Performing Mail Merge
- Working with Embedded Objects
- Importing/Exporting Emails
- Load and Save Appointment in ICS Format
- MailMessage Features
- Customizing Email Headers
- Introduction to Event Handling
- Loading eml file from disk and sending it with SMTP</Description>
              <FolderName>sendingwithsmtp</FolderName>
              <Order>1</Order>
              <Examples>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Load and Save Appointment in ICS Format</Title>
                  <Description>The Appointment class in Aspose.Email can be used to load an appointment in ICS format as well as create a new appointment and save it to disk in ICS format. In this example, creation of an appointment, saving it to disk in ICS format, and then loading it back is explained in detail.</Description>
                  <FolderName>appointmentinicsformat</FolderName>
                  <Order>1</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Load and Save Appointment in ICS Format</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Load+and+Save+Appointment+in+ICS+Format</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\test.ics</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Managing Email Attachments</Title>
                  <Description>An email attachment is a computer file which is sent along with an email message. The file may be sent as a separate message as well as a part of the message to which it is attached.
The Attachment class is used with the MailMessage class. All messages include a body. In addition to the body, you might want to send additional files. These are sent as attachments and are represented as instance of the Attachment class.

To attach an attachment to an email, please follow these steps as described in this example:

- Create an instance of the MailMessage class.
- Create an instance of the Attachment class.
- Load attachment into the Attachment instance.
- Add the Attachment instance into the MailMessage instance.</Description>
                  <FolderName>managingemailattachments</FolderName>
                  <Order>2</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Managing Email Attachments</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Managing+Email+Attachments</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <InputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\1.txt</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\1.jpg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\1.doc</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\1.pdf</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\1.rar</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </InputFiles>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\outputAttachments.msg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\outputAttachmentRemoved.msg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\attachment_1.doc</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\attachment_1.jpg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\attachment_1.pdf</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\attachment_1.rar</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Working with Embedded Objects</Title>
                  <Description>An embedded object is an object that was created with one application an enclosed within a document or file created by another application. For example, a Microsoft Excel spreadsheet can be embedded into a Microsoft Word report, or a video file can be embedded into a Microsoft PowerPoint presentation.
When a file is embedded, rather than inserted or pasted into another document, it retains its original format. The embedded document can be opened in the original application and modified.

Aspose.Email lets you work with embedded objects in emails. This example shows how to embed objects. (Extracting emails is described in Extracting Embedded Objects.)</Description>
                  <FolderName>embeddedobjects</FolderName>
                  <Order>3</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Working with Embedded Objects</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Working+with+Embedded+Objects</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <InputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\barcode.png</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </InputFiles>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\EmbeddedImage.msg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Customizing Email Headers</Title>
                  <Description>Email headers represent an Internet standard and RFC define header fields which are included in Internet email messages. An email header can be specified using the MailMessage class. Common header types are defined in the HeaderType class. It is a sealed class that works like a normal enumeration. This example provides details of customizing email header using Aspose.Email.</Description>
                  <FolderName>customizingemailheaders</FolderName>
                  <Order>4</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Customizing Email Headers</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Customizing+Email+Headers</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\MsgHeaders.msg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Sending Emails</Title>
                  <Description>The SmtpClient class allows applications to send email using the Simple Mail Transfer Protocol (SMTP). The SmptClient class is the only major entry developers use to send mail messages. The SmtpClient class also provides other common email delivery methods, including writing email messages to the file system, message queue etc.</Description>
                  <FolderName>sendingemails</FolderName>
                  <Order>5</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Sending Emails</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Sending+Emails</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Connecting to SSL Enabled SMTP Server</Title>
                  <Description>The following properties need to be set when connecting with an SMTP server with SSL support.

1: SecurityMode
2: EnableSSL
3: Port</Description>
                  <FolderName>sslenabledsmtpserver</FolderName>
                  <Order>6</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Connecting to SSL Enabled SMTP Server</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Connecting+to+SSL+Enabled+SMTP+Server</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Specifying Multiple Recipients</Title>
                  <Description>The MailMessage class represents an email message. Instances of the MailMessage class are used to construct email messages that are transmitted to an SMTP server using the SmtpClient class. This topic demonstrates how to specify more than one email addresses.

Email addresses can be specified using the MailMessage class. The email addresses used in the MailMessage class are:

1: To
2: Cc
3: Bcc</Description>
                  <FolderName>multiplerecipients</FolderName>
                  <Order>7</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Specifying Multiple Recipients</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Specifying+Multiple+Recipients</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Send Meeting Requests</Title>
                  <Description>Microsoft Outlook offers calendar functions as well as email management. When a user opens an email with an invitation to an event, Outlook prompts them to accept or reject the invitation. Aspose.Email lets developers add calendar functions to your emails.</Description>
                  <FolderName>meetingrequests</FolderName>
                  <Order>9</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Send Meeting Requests</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Send+Meeting+Requests</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Performing Mail Merge</Title>
                  <Description>Mail merges help you create and send a batch of similar email messages. The core of the emails are the same, but the content can be personalized. Typically, a recipient's contact details (first name, second name, company and so on) are used to personalize the email.</Description>
                  <FolderName>mailmerge</FolderName>
                  <Order>10</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Performing Mail Merge</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Performing+Mail+Merge</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Loading EML Files from Disk and Sending it with SMTP</Title>
                  <Description>You can load .eml files from disk or stream into the MailMessage class and send the email message using the SmtpClient class. The MailMessage class is the main class for creating new email messages, loading email message files from disk or stream and saving the messages.</Description>
                  <FolderName>sendingemlfileswithsmtp</FolderName>
                  <Order>13</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Loading EML Files from Disk and Sending it with SMTP</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Loading+EML+Files+from+Disk+and+Sending+it+with+SMTP</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <InputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\test.eml</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </InputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Load Smtp Authentication Information from Config File</Title>
                  <Description>The SmtpClient class allows applications to read authentication information like username and password and the host address and port number directly from a configuration file. Using the .NET native configuration tag, as shown below, enables the SmptClient class to read this information through the Configuration Manager also available in .NET framework.</Description>
                  <FolderName>loadsmtpconfigfile</FolderName>
                  <Order>14</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Load Smtp Authentication Information from Config File</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Load+Smtp+Authentication+Information+from+Config+File</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
              </Examples>
              <Folders>
                <Folder>
                  <Title>Set Mail Body</Title>
                  <Description>The MailMessage class represents an email message. Instances of the MailMessage class are used to construct email messages that are transmitted to a SMTP server for delivery using the SmtpClient class. A mail body can be specified using the MailMessage class. An email can have multiple bodies. There are two types of mail bodies in MailMessage class:

1: HTML body
2: Text body</Description>
                  <FolderName>setmailbody</FolderName>
                  <Order>8</Order>
                  <Examples>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Setting HTML Body</Title>
                      <Description>HtmlBody is used to specify the HTML content of a message body. HtmlBody must be enclosed between &lt;html&gt; &lt;/html&gt; tags.</Description>
                      <FolderName>settinghtmlbody</FolderName>
                      <Order>1</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Setting HTML Body</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Set+Mail+Body</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Setting Text Body</Title>
                      <Description>TextBody is used to specify textual content for a message body.</Description>
                      <FolderName>settingtextbody</FolderName>
                      <Order>2</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Setting Text Body</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Set+Mail+Body</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                  </Examples>
                </Folder>
                <Folder>
                  <Title>Importing and Exporting Emails</Title>
                  <Description>Different email servers use different email formats. To move emails between servers and email applications, it can be useful to convert them from one format to another. This article shows how to import and export email messages with Aspose.Email. Aspose.Email's MailMessage class can import email in different formats:

1: Microsoft Outlook Email Message Format (MSG).
2: Microsoft HTML Format (MHT).
3: RFC 822 Compliant Message Format (EML).
 
It can export email in different formats too:

1: RFC 822 Compliant Message Format (EML).
2: Microsoft Html Format (MHT).</Description>
                  <FolderName>importingexportingemails</FolderName>
                  <Order>11</Order>
                  <Examples>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Import EML Format Email</Title>
                      <Description>In this example, we will see how to import an EML format file using Aspose.Emails.</Description>
                      <FolderName>importeml</FolderName>
                      <Order>1</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Importing and Exporting Emails</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Importing+and+Exporting+Emails</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <InputFiles>
                        <DataFile>
                          <Path>..\data\test.eml</Path>
                        </DataFile>
                      </InputFiles>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Export Message as EML File</Title>
                      <Description>In this example we will see how we can export and email message to EML file using Aspose.Email.</Description>
                      <FolderName>exportaseml</FolderName>
                      <Order>2</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Importing and Exporting Emails</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Importing+and+Exporting+Emails</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <OutputFiles>
                        <DataFile>
                          <Path>..\data\Message.eml</Path>
                        </DataFile>
                      </OutputFiles>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                  </Examples>
                </Folder>
                <Folder>
                  <Title>Utility Features of Email Related Protocols</Title>
                  <Description>The MailMessage class represents the content of an email message. Instances of the MailMessage class are used to construct an email message that is transmitted to a SMTP server for delivery using the SmtpClient class.

In this section we have given examples of various utility features that MailMessage provides.</Description>
                  <FolderName>protocolutilityfeatures</FolderName>
                  <Order>12</Order>
                  <Examples>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Set Date, Priority and Sensitivity of Email</Title>
                      <Description>In this example we will utlilize the following features of Mail Message class:

1: Set Date and Time.
2: Set Priority.
3: Set Sensitivity.</Description>
                      <FolderName>setemailinfo</FolderName>
                      <Order>1</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>MailMessage Utility Features</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Utility+Features+of+Email+Related+Protocols</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Delivery Notifications</Title>
                      <Description>Delivery notifications let senders know that the email they sent have been delivered to the recipient's inbox. Read receipts reassure them that the recipient has opened (thus read) the email. They are often used to track that important messages have reached their audience.

In Microsoft Outlook, recipients have the option of sending or ignoring to send a read receipt to toggling the receipt on does not automatically mean that the sender will receive a receipt.</Description>
                      <FolderName>deliverynotifications</FolderName>
                      <Order>2</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Utility Features of Email Related Protocols</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Utility+Features+of+Email+Related+Protocols</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Customizing an Email Header</Title>
                      <Description>Email headers represent an Internet standard and RFC define header fields which are included in Internet email messages. An email header can be specified using the MailMessage class. Common header types are defined in the HeaderType class. It is a sealed class working like a normal enumeration.</Description>
                      <FolderName>customizingemailheader</FolderName>
                      <Order>3</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Utility Features of Email Related Protocols</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Utility+Features+of+Email+Related+Protocols</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                  </Examples>
                </Folder>
              </Folders>
            </Folder>
            <Folder>
              <Title>Aspose Email How Tos</Title>
              <Description>This section includes examples related to following topics: 

- How do I send a plain text email?
- How do I send a simple HTML email?
- How do I send email with alternate text?
- How do I request a read receipt?
- How do I specify mail body encoding?
- How do I create multiple email addresses to send email?
- How do I change email addresses to a friendly name?
- How do I add custom headers to my email?
- How do I add secret header to my email?
- How to add and save an attachment
- How to get the number of emails in the mailbox
- How to download messages
- How to delete messages
- SMTP client activity logging
- Create a Draft Appointment Request</Description>
              <FolderName>asposeemailhowtos</FolderName>
              <Order>4</Order>
              <Examples>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Create a Draft Appointment Request</Title>
                  <Description>It is often required to create an Appointment request in Draft mode, so as the basic information is added and then the same draft Appointment be forwarded to other users for necessary changes according to individual users.
In order to save an Appointment in Draft mode, the Method property of Appointment class should be set to Publish. This example demonstrates the use of this concept using Aspose.Email.</Description>
                  <FolderName>draftappointmentrequest</FolderName>
                  <Order>1</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Create a Draft Appointment Request</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Create+a+Draft+Appointment+Request</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\draftAppointment.msg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
              </Examples>
            </Folder>
            <Folder>
              <Title>Managing Email Message Files with MailMessage</Title>
              <Description>This section includes examples related to following topics: 

- Extracting Email Headers 
- Displaying Email Information on screen 
- Extracting Email Attachments 
- Extracting Embedded Objects</Description>
              <FolderName>manageemailmessages</FolderName>
              <Order>5</Order>
              <Examples>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Extracting Email Headers</Title>
                  <Description>The email header represents an Internet and RFC defined standard set of header fields included in Internet email messages. An email header can be specified using the MailMessage class. Common header types are defined in the HeaderType class. It is a sealed class working like normal enumeration.

To extract headers from an email, follow these steps:

- Create an instance of the MailMessage class.
- Load an email message in the instance of MailMessage class.
- After an email message has been loaded, we will get its raw content. The MailMessage class itself contains properties such as From, To, Cc, Subject and so on. These properties can be extracted from headers.
- Display the raw content.</Description>
                  <FolderName>extractingemailheaders</FolderName>
                  <Order>1</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Extracting Email Headers</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Extracting+Email+Headers</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <InputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\test.eml</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </InputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Displaying Email Information on Screen</Title>
                  <Description>The MailMessage represents an email message and allows developers to access email message properties. The header information (discussed in Extracting Email Headers) can be extracted and manipulated in different ways. This example explains how to display selected email header information and the email body on screen.</Description>
                  <FolderName>displayemailinformation</FolderName>
                  <Order>2</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Displaying Email Information on Screen</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Displaying+Email+Information+on+Screen</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <InputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\test.eml</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </InputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
              </Examples>
            </Folder>
            <Folder>
              <Title>Managing Email Messages with POP3</Title>
              <Description>This section includes the following examples: 

1: Connecting to POP3 Server 
2: Connecting to SSL Enabled Pop3 server 
3: Authenticating to a POP3 Server 
4: Getting Mailbox Info 
5: Receiving Emails and Saving to Disk 
6: Filtering Messages from POP3 Mailbox Based on Sender, Recipient or Date</Description>
              <FolderName>managingemailmessagespop3</FolderName>
              <Order>6</Order>
              <Examples>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Connecting to POP3 Server</Title>
                  <Description>The Pop3Client class allows applications to manage email boxes using the Post Office Protocol, Version 3 (POP3). To connect to a server, use the Pop3Client class. The Pop3Client class is the major entry for developers who want to add POP3 management to their .NET applications.</Description>
                  <FolderName>connectingtopop3</FolderName>
                  <Order>2</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Connecting to POP3 Server</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Connecting+to+POP3+Server</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Connecting to SSL Enabled POP3 Server</Title>
                  <Description>The process for connecting to an SSL enabled POP3 server requires some additional information:

1: SecurityMode
2: EnableSSL
3: Port</Description>
                  <FolderName>sslenabledpop3server</FolderName>
                  <Order>3</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Connecting to SSL Enabled POP3 Server</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Connecting+to+SSL+Enabled+POP3+Server</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Getting Mailbox Info</Title>
                  <Description>We can get information about the mailbox such as the number of messages and the mailbox size using the GetMailBoxSize() and GetMailBoxInfo() methods.

1: The GetMailBoxSize() method returns the size of the mailbox in bytes.
2: The GetMailBoxInfo() method returns an object of type Pop3MailBoxInfo.

It is also possible to get the number of messages using the MessageCount property and the size using the OccupiedSize property.</Description>
                  <FolderName>gettingmailboxinfo</FolderName>
                  <Order>4</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Getting Mailbox Info</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Getting+Mailbox+Info</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
              </Examples>
              <Folders>
                <Folder>
                  <Title>Receiving Emails and Saving to Disk</Title>
                  <Description>This section includes examples which demonstrate how to recieve emails, save them and parse them for information.</Description>
                  <FolderName>receivingandsavingtodisk</FolderName>
                  <Order>1</Order>
                  <Examples>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Retrieving Email Headers</Title>
                      <Description>Email headers can give us information about an email message that we can use to decide whether or not to retrieve the whole email message. Typically, the header information contains sender, subject, received date etc.</Description>
                      <FolderName>retrievingemailheaders</FolderName>
                      <Order>1</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Receiving Emails and Saving to Disk</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Receiving+Emails+and+Saving+to+Disk</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Retrieving Email Messages</Title>
                      <Description>Aspose.Email.Pop3 component provides the capability to retrieve email messages from the POP3 server, and parse them into a MailMessage instance with the help of Aspose.Email.Mail components. The MailMessage class contains several properties and methods for manipulating email content. By using the Pop3Client class' FetchMessage function, you can get a MailMessage instance directly from the POP3 server.</Description>
                      <FolderName>retrievingemailmessages</FolderName>
                      <Order>2</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Receiving Emails and Saving to Disk</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Receiving+Emails+and+Saving+to+Disk</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Save Message to Disk without Parsing</Title>
                      <Description>If you want to download email messages from the POP3 server without parsing them, use the Pop3Client class' SaveMessage function. The SaveMessage function does not parse the email message so it is faster than the FetchMessage function.</Description>
                      <FolderName>savetodiskwithoutparsing</FolderName>
                      <Order>3</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Receiving Emails and Saving to Disk</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Receiving+Emails+and+Saving+to+Disk</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <OutputFiles>
                        <DataFile>
                          <Path>..\data\1234.eml</Path>
                        </DataFile>
                      </OutputFiles>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Parse Message Before Saving</Title>
                      <Description>The following sample uses the Pop3Client's FetchMessage method to retrieve a message from a POP3 server by its sequence number, then save the message to disk using the subject as the file name.</Description>
                      <FolderName>parsemessageandsave</FolderName>
                      <Order>4</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Receiving Emails and Saving to Disk</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Receiving+Emails+and+Saving+to+Disk</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <OutputFiles>
                        <DataFile>
                          <Path>..\data\Msg1234.eml</Path>
                        </DataFile>
                      </OutputFiles>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Getting Recipient Information</Title>
                      <Description>The MapiRecipient class represents the sender or recipient information of the email message, which contains:* RecipientType indicates the type of the recipient.* DisplayName a string represents the display name of the recipient.* EmailAddress a string array represents the email address of the recipient.
To query the mailbox status:# Create a MapiMessage instance by loading from files or stream.# Get the MapiRecipient from MapiMessage.Recipients.</Description>
                      <FolderName>recipientinformation</FolderName>
                      <Order>5</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Receiving Emails and Saving to Disk</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Receiving+Emails+and+Saving+to+Disk</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <InputFiles>
                        <DataFile>
                          <Path>..\data\Message.msg</Path>
                        </DataFile>
                      </InputFiles>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                  </Examples>
                </Folder>
              </Folders>
            </Folder>
            <Folder>
              <Title>Managing Emails with IMAP</Title>
              <Description>This section includes the following examples: 

1: Connecting with IMAP Server 
2: Connecting with SSL enabled Imap Server 
3: Fetch Messages from Imap Server and Save to Disk 
4: Delete Messages 
5: Changing the Message Flags 
6: Adding a New Message in a Folder 
7: Getting Folders Information 
8: Deleting and Renaming Folders 
9: Get Folder and Sub-folders Information from IMAP Server and Read Messages Recursively 
10: Filtering Messages from IMAP Mailbox Based on Sender, Recipient or Date</Description>
              <FolderName>managingemailswithimap</FolderName>
              <Order>6</Order>
              <Examples>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Connecting with IMAP Server</Title>
                  <Description>The ImapClient class allows applications to manage IMAP mailboxs using the IMAP protocol. The ImapClient class is used to connect to IMAP mail servers and manage emails in the IMAP email folders.</Description>
                  <FolderName>connectingwithimapserver</FolderName>
                  <Order>1</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Connecting with IMAP Server</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Connecting+with+IMAP+Server</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Connecting with SSL Enabled IMAP Server</Title>
                  <Description>In this example, we will see how to connect with IMAP Server with SSL Enabled. The process for connecting to an SSL enables IMAP server requires following additional information:

1: SecurityMode
2: EnableSSL
3: Port</Description>
                  <FolderName>sslenabledimapserver</FolderName>
                  <Order>2</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Connecting with SSL Enabled IMAP Server</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Connecting+with+SSL+Enabled+IMAP+Server</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Fetch Messages from IMAP Server and Save to Disk</Title>
                  <Description>The ImapClient class can fetch messages from an IMAP server and save the messages in EML format to a local disk.</Description>
                  <FolderName>messagesfromimapservertodisk</FolderName>
                  <Order>3</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Fetch Messages from IMAP Server and Save to Disk</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Fetch+Messages+from+IMAP+Server+and+Save+to+Disk</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\1.eml</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Setting Message Flags</Title>
                  <Description>You can change message flags by using the ChangeMessageFlags() method. This method takes two parameters. 

1.The message sequence number or unique ID.
2.MessageFlag.
 
The following flags can be set:

1: Answered
2: Deleted
3: Draft
4: Empty
5: Flagged
6: IsRead
7: Readed
8: Recent</Description>
                  <FolderName>settingmessageflags</FolderName>
                  <Order>4</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Changing the Message Flags</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Changing+the+Message+Flags</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Removing Message Flags</Title>
                  <Description>Message flags can also be removed with the RemoveMessageFlags() method. Usage is similar to that of the ChangeMessageFlags() method. It takes a sequence number or unique message ID and MessageFlag.</Description>
                  <FolderName>removingmessageflags</FolderName>
                  <Order>5</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Changing the Message Flags</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Changing+the+Message+Flags</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Adding a New Message in a Folder</Title>
                  <Description>Developers can add a new message to the folder using the MailMessage and ImapClient classes of Aspose.Email.</Description>
                  <FolderName>addingnewmessage</FolderName>
                  <Order>6</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Adding a New Message in a Folder</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Adding+a+New+Message+in+a+Folder</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Getting Folders Information</Title>
                  <Description>Getting information about folders from an IMAP server is very easy with Aspose.Email. Call the Aspose.Email.Imap namespace ListFolders() method. It returns an object of the ImapFolderInfoCollection type. Iterate through this collection and get information about individual folders in a loop. The method is overloaded. You can pass a folder name as a parameter to get a list of subfolders.</Description>
                  <FolderName>gettingfoldersinformation</FolderName>
                  <Order>7</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Getting Folders Information</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Getting+Folders+Information</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Get Folder Information from IMAP Server and Read Messages Recursively</Title>
                  <Description>In this example, most of the ImapClient features are used to create an application that lists all the folders and sub-folders recursively from an IMAP server. It also saves the messages in each folder and sub-folder in MSG format on a local disk. In disk, folders and messages are created and saved in the same hierarchical structure as on the IMAP server.</Description>
                  <FolderName>readmessagesrecursively</FolderName>
                  <Order>9</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Get Folder and Sub folders Information from IMAP Server and Read Messages Recursively</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Get+Folder+and+Sub+folders+Information+from+IMAP+Server+and+Read+Messages+Recursively</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <InputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\inbox\Test Email-4.msg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </InputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
              </Examples>
              <Folders>
                <Folder>
                  <Title>Deleting and Renaming Folders</Title>
                  <Description>This section includes the following examples:</Description>
                  <FolderName>deletingandrenamingfolders</FolderName>
                  <Order>8</Order>
                  <Examples>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Renaming Folders</Title>
                      <Description>Aspose.Email allows developers to rename folders. Call the RenameFolder() method,and pass the current folder name and new folder name.</Description>
                      <FolderName>renamingfolders</FolderName>
                      <Order>1</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Deleting and Renaming Folders</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Deleting+and+Renaming+Folders</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                    <Example>
                      <Title>Deleting Folders</Title>
                      <Description>A folder on an IMAP server can be deleted with a single line using Aspose.Email. Developer can pass folder name as parameter to DeleteFolder() method to delete a specific folder.</Description>
                      <FolderName>deletingfolders</FolderName>
                      <Order>2</Order>
                      <DocLink>
                        <DisplayName>Deleting and Renaming Folders</DisplayName>
                        <Url>Deleting+and+Renaming+Folders</Url>
                      </DocLink>
                      <Type>Console</Type>
                    </Example>
                  </Examples>
                </Folder>
              </Folders>
            </Folder>
          </Folders>
        </Folder>
        <Folder>
          <Title>Programming Outlook</Title>
          <Description>This section includes examples related to the following topics: 

- Your First Application with Aspose.Email.Outlook 
- Managing Message Files with Aspose.Email.Outlook</Description>
          <FolderName>programmingoutlook</FolderName>
          <Order>2</Order>
          <Folders>
            <Folder>
              <Title>Managing Message Files with Aspose.Email.Outlook</Title>
              <Description>This section includes the examples related to following topics: 

- Loading, Viewing and Parsing Outlook Message (MSG) File
- Accessing Outlook MAPI Property
- Reading Named MAPI Properties from Outlook Message (MSG) Files
- Creating and Saving Outlook Message (MSG) Files
- EML to MSG Converter
- Managing Attachments with Aspose Outlook
- Read Outlook Template File (.OFT)
- Using Aspose Outlook Control to Drag &amp; Drop Outlook Messages to Windows Forms
- Read Outlook PST File and Get Folder and Subfolder Information
- Read Outlook OST File
- Get Message Information from an Outlook PST File
- Extract Messages from Outlook PST Files and Save to Disk or Stream in MSG Format
- Access Contact Information from Outlook PST File and Save to Disk in MSG format
- Save Contacts Information from Outlook PST to Disk in vCard format (VCF)
- Save Calendar Items from Outlook PST to Disk in ICS format
- Create a New PST File and Add Subfolders
- Add Messages to PST Files
- Delete Messages from PST Files
- Check if a PST is password protected</Description>
              <FolderName>managemessagefiles</FolderName>
              <Order>1</Order>
              <Examples>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Create a New PST File and Add Subfolders</Title>
                  <Description>As well as parsing an existing PST file, Aspose.Email provides the means to create a PST file from scratch. This example  demonstrates how to create an Outlook PST file and add a subfolder to it.</Description>
                  <FolderName>newpstaddsubfolders</FolderName>
                  <Order>1</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Create a New PST File and Add Subfolders</DisplayName>
                    <Url>Create+a+New+PST+File+and+Add+Subfolders</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\PersonalStorage.pst</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
              </Examples>
            </Folder>
            <Folder>
              <Title>Working with Outlook Message (MSG) Files</Title>
              <Description>This section includes examples related to the following topics: 

- Parsing Outlook Message Files
- Accessing Outlook MAPI Properties
- Parsing and Saving Attachments
- Read Outlook Template File (.OFT)
- Creating and Saving Outlook Message (MSG) Files</Description>
              <FolderName>workwithoutlookmsgfiles</FolderName>
              <Order>2</Order>
              <Examples>
                <Example>
                  <Title>Creating and Saving Outlook Message (MSG) Files</Title>
                  <Description>Aspose.Email also supports creating an outlook message (msg) files. The MailMessage class has the save() method that can save the outlook msg file to disk or stream. In this example, we will create an instance of the MailMessage class, set some properties like from, to, subject, body and save it.</Description>
                  <FolderName>createsaveoutlookfiles</FolderName>
                  <Order>1</Order>
                  <DocLink>
                    <DisplayName>Creating and Saving Outlook Message (MSG) Files</DisplayName>
                    <Url>http://www.aspose.com/docs/display/EmailJava/Creating+and+Saving+Outlook+Message+(MSG)+Files</Url>
                  </DocLink>
                  <OutputFiles>
                    <DataFile>
                      <Path>..\data\message.msg</Path>
                    </DataFile>
                  </OutputFiles>
                  <Type>Console</Type>
                </Example>
              </Examples>
            </Folder>
          </Folders>
        </Folder>
      </Folders>
    </Folder>
    <Folder>
      <Title>Knowledge Base</Title>
      <Description>This section includes the examples related to following topics: 

- Technical Articles
- Migration from Office Automation to Aspose
- Utilizing Aspose.Email for .NET in other Programming Languages</Description>
      <FolderName>knowledgebase</FolderName>
      <Order>2</Order>
      <Examples>
        <Example>
          <Title>Aspose.Email.Printing Features</Title>
          <Description>The Aspose.Email.Printing namespace provides a rich set of features for printing mail messages to different formats (XPS or TIFF) and configuring page layouts. This examples describes these features in detail. Following are the key features explained by example:

- Printing the message body only.
- Printing the message body and headers.
- Printing an HTML body.
- Setting the page layout.
- Auto-fit a TIFF to the printer.</Description>
          <FolderName>printingfeatures</FolderName>
          <Order>1</Order>
          <DocLink>
            <DisplayName>Aspose.Email.Printing Features</DisplayName>
            <Url>Aspose.Email.Printing+Features</Url>
          </DocLink>
          <OutputFiles>
            <DataFile>
              <Path>..\data\test.tiff</Path>
            </DataFile>
            <DataFile>
              <Path>..\data\test.xps</Path>
            </DataFile>
          </OutputFiles>
          <Type>Console</Type>
        </Example>
      </Examples>
    </Folder>
  </Folders>
</Data>