<!--
  ~ @author Adeel Ilyas <adeel.ilyas@aspose.com>
  -->
<idea-plugin version="2">
    <id>com.aspose.email.java.intellij.maven</id>
    <name>Aspose.Email Java for IntelliJ IDEA Maven</name>
    <version>1.0.0.0</version>
    <vendor email="email@aspose.com" url="http://www.aspose.com">Aspose Pty Ltd.</vendor>


    <description><![CDATA[<br/><b>Aspose.Email for Java</b> API allows developers to create as well as read message files, enabling complete processing of message contents. <br/><br/><b>Aspose.Email for Java</b> enables you to create, read and manipulate Outlook MSG, PST, EML, EMLX and MHT files from within a Java application without the need of using Microsoft Outlook. The API also allows connecting to email servers and send/receive emails. It's support for POP3, IMAP and SMTP protocols provide complete capability of working with SSL as well as non-SSL email servers. <br/><br/>The plugin's <b>Aspose.Email Maven Project</b> wizard lets you create a Aspose.Email Java API maven project by fetching & referencing the latest API mvn artifact from the Aspose Cloud Maven Repository.<br/><br/>Plugin provided wizards also gives you option to download & import the example source codes for using Aspose.Email for Java API.<br/><br/>After the completion of wizard, project will be created and API examples are downloaded. All references and required resources will also be automatically added to the project.<br/><br/>You can then import / use codes (using option <b>File-> New-> Aspose.Email Example</b>) from downloaded examples for your project needs and enhance them as necessary.<br/>
    ]]></description>


    <!-- please see http://confluence.jetbrains.com/display/IDEADEV/Build+Number+Ranges for description -->
    <idea-version since-build="139"/>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <moduleBuilder builderClass="com.aspose.wizards.maven.AsposeMavenModuleBuilder"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action id="aspose.email.example" class="com.aspose.examples.AsposeExampleAction" text="Aspose.Email Example" icon="/resources/asposeSmall.png"
                description="Aspose.Email Examples allow you to add Aspose sourcecode examples to demonstrate Aspose.Email Java API usage. Available samples are displayed in tree format from where you can select one. Selected category examples will be added to current project including source files and required data files.">
            <add-to-group group-id="NewGroup" anchor="first"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>